# Luca Fortini

Born in Rome on August 1st 1994 - Nationality: Italian Current Address: Via Caffaro 12/A, 16124 Genova, Italy

Mobile phone: +39 3297877947 E-mail: <a href="mailto:lucafortini60@gmail.com/">lucafortini60@gmail.com</a>
Linkedin: <a href="mailto:www.linkedin.com/">www.linkedin.com/</a>in/luca-fortini/
GitHub: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/4TINI">https://github.com/4TINI</a>

Personal Website/Portfolio: <a href="https://4tini.github.io/lucafortini/">https://4tini.github.io/lucafortini/</a>

#### PROFILE

I am a biomedical engineering master's student with a research interest in rehabilitation and medical devices' design. Thanks to the involvement in several associations and my lifelong scout experience I feel comfortable in a teamwork environment.

### **EDUCATION**

| 2016 - Present | Politecnico di Milano - Master in Biomedical Engineering                   |
|----------------|--|
| 2013 - 2016    | University of Rome "La Sapienza" - Bachelor Degree in Clinical Engineering |
| 2013           | Liceo Scientifico Morgagni - High School Degree                            |

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK AND ACTIVITIES**

| 2017 - Present | Co-founder and board member, BEA (Biomedical Engineering                |
|----------------|---|
|                | Association), student association                                       |
| 2018 - Present | IEEE member and Co-founder of IEEE EMB Student Branch Chapter at        |
|                | Politecnico di Milano   |
| 2012 - 2016    | Chief Scout, AGESCI, Rome, Italy  |
| 2013 - 2016    | Basketball Coach, project "Basket & Disability", Smit club, Rome, Italy |
| 2013 - 2014    | Volunteer, ONG OXFAM, Rome Italy  |
|                | Fundraising, Information and Propaganda                                 |
| 2012 - 2013    | Volunteer, Community of St.Egidio, Rome, Italy                          |
|                | Administrative work, data collecting                                    |
| 2012 - 2014    | Agonistic sport, Beach Volley, Monteverde Club, Rome, Italy             |
| 2003 - 2012    | Scouting, AGESCI, Rome, Italy   |
| 2008 - 2012    | Agonistic sport, Basketball, Vigna Pia, Rome, Italy                     |

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

| December 2018 - Present  | <b>Internship at Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia</b> , Genova, Italy |
|--------------------------|--|
| May 2016 - November 2017 | Internship at IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana, Rome, Italy                 |

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Italian: mother tongue

English: fluent, English Language Testing System (IELTS) Academic, score 8/9, level C1

French: comprehension and elementary communication Spanish: comprehension and elementary communication

### **COMPUTER AND ELECTRONIC SKILLS**

Application and software: Processing, Solidworks, Opensim, Android Studio, Ansys, Abaqus

Programming language: Matlab, C, LaTeX, Simulink, Java Electronics: Microcontroller Programming (Arduino)

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Other working experience: private lessons of maths and physics (2013 - 2018)

Other course and seminar: "Extreme Sports & Engineering" Summer School, Lecco, Italy